Robbie Perlstein

robbie.perlstein@gmail.com | robbiep.com | github.com/robbiep

Summary

The journey from Software Engineer I to Software Development Manager in less than 3 years at Shutterstock underscores my bias for action and thirst for accomplishment.

Technical Skills

Regular Usage: Javascript/Node, Perl, Ruby, SQL, REST, SOA, Linux

Notable Usage: Puppet, Chef, Apache, Nginx, Java, C++, Python, HTML/CSS, Android

Experience

SHUTTERSTOCK August 2016 - Present

Software Development Manager & Tech Lead

- Tech owner of three back-end services and three legacy application stacks.
- Work closely with Product and Design to transform our vision into deliverable milestones.
- Conduct technical interviews, lead scrum ceremonies, helm stakeholder communications, take ownership of team successes and failures, support on call duties, and fight fires.

SHUTTERSTOCK June 2014 - July 2016

Software Engineer

- Technical leader and project manager on multiple initiatives.
 - Managed development of a product that resulted in \$18 million annualized revenue.
 - Planned work for a team to migrate a core feature set and associated data from a legacy monolith to an external service, using dual writes and an ETL.
 - Designed and lead development of a RESTful API service in Node.js and MySql.
- Increased re-conversion rates by 18.5% and increased retention rates by 14.5%.

ZERISTA April 2013 – March 2014

Ruby on Rails Developer

• Supported and grew a large, templated Rails application during a massive migration of the client-facing views, admin dashboard, and iOS/Android native applications.

ENODIA FINANCIAL TECHNOLOGY

June 2012 - December 2012

Jr. Java Developer

• Developed real-time, server-side, FpML, financial transaction reporting software in compliance with international standards required by the Dodd-Frank Act of 2010.

Education

B.S. Computer Science and Engineering, *Special Honors* University of Colorado, Denver

May 2014